Guide to the Thornton Wilder Collection
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Materials from Other Sources, 1918-1975; Series X; 0.84; (3 boxes)
  - WRITINGS AND OTHER PAPERS
    - Writings
      - The Victors: signed contract between TW and the Dramatists' Guild of the Authors' League, 1948 Dec 15 (Box 9, Folder 191)
        With TL carbon letter of intent signed by TW, n.d.
        Acc: 19990108-b
      - The Woman of Andros: setting typescript carbon, corrected, annotated (Box 9, Folder 192)
        Acc: 19520208
    - Other Papers
      - Cyanotype of "Todger" (pony), [1912-13?] (Box 9, Folder 193)
        Annotated in hand of IW: "Thornton's pony at Thacher"
      - Newspaper clippings, 1959-62 (Box 9, Folder 194)
      - Printed material, 1932-62 (Box 9, Folder 195)
        Includes dust jacket of Marion Preminger's All I Want Is Everything inscribed to TW
        Acc: 19640520-
      - ALS to "Mr. Stryker;" Nantucket, Mass., 1946 Jul 3 (Box 16, Folder 264)
        Acc: 20020729-n
      - ALS to "Dear Fanny;" Havana, Cuba, [1952] Dec 15 (Box 16, Folder 265)
        Acc: 20020829-d
      - ALS to Samuel French; Hotel Lincoln, New York, 1939 Jan 18 (Box 16, Folder 266)
        Acc: 20020829-e
      - ALS to "Mr. Freedley;" University of Chicago, 1934 Jun 11 (Box 16, Folder 267)
        Concerning background for Bridge: "I know nothing about the theater of Peru."
        Acc: 20020829-f
      - APCS to Paul Osborne; Newport, 1927 Jul 18 (Box 16, Folder 268)
        Acc: 20020829-g
      - ALS to "Mr. Van Loon;" New York, 1947 Aug 23 (Box 16, Folder 269)
        Acc: 20020829-h
      - ALS to Marshall Lee; Hamden, Conn., 1960 Mar 14 (Box 16, Folder 270)
        Acc: 20020829-i
      - 3 ALS to Edita Imperatori and Franco Spinosi; 50 Deepwood Drive, Hamden, 1959-69 (Box 16, Folder 271)
        With: 3 ALS from Isabel Wilder to Edita Imperatori and her mother, "Mrs. Imperatori," and enclosure of TLS to IW from Washington Center of Foreign Policy Research, 1959
        Acc: 20020913-a
      - ALS to "Dear Margaret;" Douglas, Arizona, 1963 Aug 6 (Box 16, Folder 272)
        Acc: 20021017-ae
      - Watercolor design by Rockwell Kent for endpapers of a limited edition of Bridge of San Luis Rey, [ca. 1936] (Box 16, Folder 273)
        With: holograph note by Rockwell Kent
        Acc: 20021115-a
      - 2 ALS and 1 TLS to Sara Glass, 1951, n.d. (Box 16, Folder 274)
        With: clipping from Time magazine concerning Wilder, 1951 Jul 2
        Acc: 20010925-b
      - APCS to J. F. Stephens; Hamden, 1948 Aug 25 (Box 16, Folder 275)
        Acc: 20011016-b
      - ALS to Paul Osborn; 75 Mansfield St., New Haven, 1928 Jan 11 (Box 16, Folder 276)
        Concerning possible ill-effects of bootleg liquor. With: envelope. Acc: 20011016-c
      - ALS to Mrs. Eckert; Lawrenceville, [ca. 1927?] (Box 16, Folder 277)
        Acc: 20011016-d
      - Studio portrait of Thornton Wilder, n.d. (Box 16, Folder 278)
        Stamped on verso: Tappan Wilder With: envelope. Acc: 20030205-v
      - "Foreward" to "The Happy Journey to Trenton from Camden", 1945 Jul (Box 16, Folder 279)
        Holograph, corrected and signed, of the 1945 "Foreward" to an edition of the play. Inscribed: "For George Kelley, cordially, Thornton Wilder Oct 25, 1945." With: typescript carbon, corrected. Acc: 20030522-b
      - "The Angel on the Ship", n.d. (Box 16, Folder 280)
        Holograph, corrected and signed, of a version of this 1928 "Three- Minute" play. With: typescript carbon, corrrected, of the "Forward" to "The Angel that Troubled the Waters." Acc: 20030522-f
      - "Childe Roland to the Dark Tower Came" (Box 16, Folder 281)
        Holograph, corrected and signed. With: bill from C.A. Stonehill for George Kelley, 1941 Jul 22 Acc: 20030522-e
      - "The Flight into Egypt", n.d. (Box 16, Folder 282)
        Holograph, corrected and signed. Acc: 20030522-d
      - "Mozart and the Gray Steward" (Box 16, Folder 283)
        Holograph, corrected and signed. Acc: 20030522-c
      - The Woman of Andros, 1930 (Box 16, Folder 284)
        Manuscript copy in an unidentified hand of the 1930 edition. In fabric wrapper. With: Newspaper clipping of review of novel by Martin Hare, 1933 Feb 26 (review by Louise Maunsell Field). Acc: 20030812-l
      - Photograph of Thornton Wilder and group (Box 16, Folder 285)
        Annotated by TW on verso. Acc: 20030922-h
      - 4 ALS to Charlotte Burroughs Lincoln, 1927-46 (Box 16, Folder 286)
        Acc: 19971008-l
      - "Our Century:" author's proof, 1947 (Box 16, Folder 287)
        With: ms. note by Thomas J. Wilson. Acc: 20040209-ce
      - ALS to Leonard Nathan; 50 Deepwood Drive, Hamden, 1975 Oct 28 (Box 16, Folder 288)
        With: envelope. Acc: 20040512-a
      - 10 ALS to Gilbert Miller, 1932-49 (Box 16, Folder 289)
        With: TL to TW from Miller. With: typed transcripts. Acc.: 20040512-b
      - 9 ALS to Mia Farrow, 1969-74 (Box 16, Folder 290)
        With: 8 envelopes. Acc.: 20040819-b
      - ALS to Miss Mears; 50 Deepwood Drive, Hamden, CT, 1948 Jul 4 (Box 16, Folder 291)
        Concerning properties for a production of The Skin of Our Teeth. With: printed photograph of TW as Mr. Antrobus. Acc.: 20040524-bd
      - ALS to Leonard Lyons; Douglas, Arizona, 1963 Jul 14 (Box 16, Folder 292)
        Describes life in Douglas; praises Lyons's columns With: photocopy of ALS to "Jacob" mentioning clippings sent by Lyons to TW, original dated 1963 Oct 10 With: envelope Acc: 20050621-f
      - 2 ALS and APcS to Henry Luce, 1926-33 (Box 16, Folder 293)
        Greetings, thanks for articles and social notes; letter of 1926 Sep 9 discusses The Cabala and reviews of it With: 1 envelope Acc: 20060125-a
      - 3 ALS and telegram to Lila Luce Tyng, 1928-55 (Box 16, Folder 294)
        Notes concerning social engagement; 1955 letter describes his love of the Rhône valley With: APcS from Isobel Wilder to Lila Luce Tyng, 1948 Dec 6 With: 2 envelopes Acc: 20060125-a
      - ALS to Edna Ferber; 50 Deepwood Drive, New Haven, Connecticut, 1933 Mar 21 (Box 16, Folder 295)
        Praise of Ferber as "the truest Chicagoan of them all;" regrets he is unable to meet her on Friday Acc: 3622
      - 13 ALS and 4 APcS to Harry Traugott, 1945-74 (Box 16, Folder 296)
        Lengthy letters containing personal news and discussion of events in Traugott's life; 1945-46 letters discuss TW's Army experiences Acc: 3631
      - 3 ALS to Simon Blow, 1973-74 (Box 16, Folder 297)
        Lengthy letters discussing his work in reply to a young journalist's questions. Subjects include The Eighth Day; the necessity of travel for writers; and Theophilus North and "the ambiguities of ethics." With: 3 envelopes Acc: 6424
- Oversize, 1968
  - Galley proofs of Harper edition, 1968 (Box 10, Folder 196)
  - Page proofs of Harper editions, 1968 (Box 11, Folder 197)
  - Dust jacket proof, 1928 (Box 12, Folder 198)
  - Uncorrected galley proof, 1967 (Box 13, Folder 199)
- Restricted Fragile, 0.63; (2 boxes)
  Conditions Governing Access
  Restricted fragile material. Reference surrogates have been substituted in the main files. For further information consult the appropriate curator.
  - Box 2, folder 33 (Box 14, Folder 200)
  - Box 2, folder 34 (Box 14, Folder 201)
  - Box 2, folder 35 (Box 14, Folder 202)
  - Box 2, folder 37 (Box 14, Folder 203)
  - Box 2, folder 43 (Box 14, Folder 204)
  - Box 3, folder 50 (Box 14, Folder 205)
  - Box 3, folder 52 (Box 14, Folder 206)
  - Box 3, folder 53 (Box 14, Folder 207)
  - Box 3, folder 54 (Box 14, Folder 208)
  - Box 3, folder 57 (Box 14, Folder 209)
  - Box 3, folder 59 (Box 14, Folder 210)
  - Box 3, folder 60 (Box 14, Folder 211)
  - Box 3, folder 66 (Box 14, Folder 212)
  - Box 4, folder 68 (Box 14, Folder 213)
  - Box 4, folder 69 (Box 14, Folder 214)
  - Box 4, folder 71 (Box 14, Folder 215)
  - Box 4, folder 72 (Box 14, Folder 216)
  - Box 4, folder 73 (Box 14, Folder 217)
  - Box 4, folder 75 (Box 14, Folder 218)
  - Box 4, folder 84 (Box 14, Folder 219)
  - Box 4, folder 88 (Box 14, Folder 220)
  - Box 5, folder 93 (Box 14, Folder 221)
  - Box 5, folder 94 (Box 14, Folder 222)
  - Box 5, folder 95 (Box 14, Folder 223)
  - Box 5, folder 96 (Box 14, Folder 224)
  - Box 5, folder 97 (Box 14, Folder 225)
  - Box 5, folder 98 (Box 14, Folder 226)
  - Box 5, folder 99 (Box 14, Folder 227)
  - Box 5, folder 100 (Box 14, Folder 228)
  - Box 5, folder 101 (Box 14, Folder 229)
  - Box 5, folder 102 (Box 14, Folder 230)
  - Box 5, folder 103 (Box 14, Folder 231)
  - Box 5, folder 104 (Box 14, Folder 232)
  - Box 5, folder 105 (Box 14, Folder 233)
  - Box 5, folder 106 (Box 14, Folder 234)
  - Box 5, folder 107 (Box 14, Folder 235)
  - Box 5, folder 109 (Box 14, Folder 236)
  - Box 5, folder 110 (Box 14, Folder 237)
  - Box 5, folder 111 (Box 14, Folder 238)
  - Box 5, folder 112 (Box 14, Folder 239)
  - Box 5, folder 113 (Box 14, Folder 240)
  - Box 5, folder 116 (Box 14, Folder 241)
  - Box 5, folder 118 (Box 14, Folder 242)
  - Box 7, folder 164 (Box 14, Folder 243)
  - Box 7, folder 165 (Box 14, Folder 244)
  - Box 7, folder 167 (Box 14, Folder 245)
  - Box 7, folder 172 (Box 14, Folder 246)
  - Box 8, folder 173 (Box 14, Folder 247)
  - Box 8, folder 174 (Box 14, Folder 248)
  - Box 8, folder 175 (Box 14, Folder 249)
  - Box 8, folder 176 (Box 14, Folder 250)
  - Box 8, folder 177 (Box 14, Folder 251)
  - Box 8, folder 178 (Box 14, Folder 252)
  - Box 8, folder 179 (Box 14, Folder 253)
  - Box 8, folder 180 (Box 15, Folder 254)
  - Box 8, folder 181 (Box 15, Folder 255)
  - Box 8, folder 182 (Box 15, Folder 256)
  - Box 8, folder 183 (Box 15, Folder 257)
  - Box 8, folder 184 (Box 15, Folder 258)
  - Box 8, folder 185 (Box 15, Folder 259)
  - Box 8, folder 186 (Box 15, Folder 260)
  - Box 8, folder 187 (Box 15, Folder 261)
  - Box 9, folder 192 (Box 15, Folder 262)
  - Box 9, folder 193 (Box 15, Folder 263)